export const questions = [
	//Choice 1
	[
		{
			id: 1,
			question:
				'This Nobel Prize winning book became popular in the West and was widely translated. The name of the book meant ‘An offering of songs’ in English. It a famous collection of poems by Rabindranath Tagore. Identify this anthology i.e. Collection of Poems',
			answer: 'Gitanjali'
		},
		{
			id: 2,
			question:
				'It is the most abundant chemical substance in the Universe. Name this element having its meaning ‘Water Former’ in Greek.',
			answer: 'Hydrogen'
		}
	],
	//Choice 2
	[
		{
			id: 1,
			question:
				'He is an Indian author of British Descent who is recognized for his role in the growth of children’s literature in India. Identify this well known author.',
			answer: 'Ruskin Bond'
		},
		{
			id: 2,
			question:
				'Located in Aurangabad Maharashtra, commissioned by Aurangazeb’s Son Azam in the memory of his mother Dilras Banu Begam, this tomb was designed & erected by Ata – Ullah. Name this famous tomb.',
			answer: 'Bibi ka Maqbara'
		}
	],
	//Choice 3
	[
		{
			id: 1,
			question:
				'The flag of Brazil is a blue disc depicting a starry sky spanned by a curved band inscribed with the national motto, within a yellow Rhombus on a green field. What is their famous national motto?',
			answer: 'Ordem e Progresso (Order & Progress)'
		},
		{
			id: 2,
			question:
				'The largest Indian river is the first non – human entity in India to be granted the same legal rights as that of the human beings. Which river are we referring to?',
			answer: 'River Ganga'
		}
	],
	//Choice 4
	[
		{
			id: 1,
			question:
				'Identify the French Mathematician who proposed the Cartesian Co-ordinate System to describe the position of a point in a plane accurately. The word Cartesian is derived from his name.',
			answer: 'Rene Descartes'
		},
		{
			id: 2,
			question:
				'This instrument is believed to be developed by improving upon the Pungi (a wood wind folk instrument used primarily for Snake charming). Which is this famous instrument?',
			answer: 'Shehnai'
		}
	],
	//Choice 5
	[
		{
			id: 1,
			question:
				'She is known for her fundamental work in Statistics and also, is the founder of Modern Nursing. Identify this great woman.',
			answer: 'Florence Nightingle'
		},
		{
			id: 2,
			question:
				'‘For the Game, For the World’ is the motto of an International organization related to the game of football, with the most number of member nations. Which is this Organisation?',
			answer: 'FIFA'
		}
	],
	//Choice 6
	[
		{
			id: 1,
			question:
				'In 1876, the Prince of Wales & Queen Victoria visited India on a tour. Since this colour denotes Hospitality, the then King Maharaja Ram Singh painted the whole city in this color to welcome the guests. The tradition has been sincerely followed by the residents, who are by now, compelled to maintain this.Identify this famous Indian city.',
			answer: 'Jaipur, The Pink City'
		},
		{
			id: 2,
			question:
				'Identify the monument located in Delhi which is designed as a 9 sided flower like circular structure whose large interior space is reserved for people of all faiths to come & meditate. Identify this famous monument.',
			answer: 'Lotus Temple'
		}
	]
];
